About a decade ago, the G-20, a forum of the world’s biggest economies, agreed to crack down on multinational corporations’ abusive use of tax havens.
大约十年前，二十国集团（由世界最大经济体组成的论坛）同意严厉打击跨国公司滥用避税天堂的行为。
This resulted in a plan that aimed to curb practices that shielded a large chunk of corporate profits from tax authorities.
这促成了一项计划，旨在遏制那些让很大一部分公司利润避开税务机关的做法。
But, instead of the plan reining in the use of tax havens—countries such as the Bahamas and Cayman Islands with very low or no effective tax rates—the problem has only gotten worse.
但是，这项计划非但没能控制住利用避税天堂（巴哈马、开曼群岛等实际税率很低或为零的国家）的行为，问题反而越发严重了。
In a new study, we measured the excessive profits reported in tax havens that cannot be explained by ordinary economic activity such as employees, factories and research in those countries.
在一项新研究中，我们测算了在避税天堂申报的超额利润，这些利润无法用当地员工、工厂、研究等正常经济活动来解释。
Our findings show a striking pattern of artificial shifting of paper profits to tax havens by corporations, which has been relentless since the 1980s.
我们的研究结果显示出一种惊人的模式：公司人为地把账面利润转移到避税天堂，这种转移自20世纪80年代以来从未停歇。
We found that the world’s biggest multinational businesses shifted 37% of the profits—$969 billion—they earned in other countries to tax havens in 2019.
我们发现，2019年，世界最大的跨国企业把在其他国家所获利润中的37%（即9690亿美元）转移到了避税天堂。
The figure was less than 2% in the 1970s.
20世纪70年代，这一数字还不到2%。
The main reasons for the large increase were the growth of the tax avoidance industry in the 1980s and U.S. policies that made it easier to shift profits from high-tax countries to tax havens.
这一数字大幅上升的主要原因有两个：一是20世纪80年代避税行业的发展壮大，二是美国的政策使利润更容易从高税率国家转移到避税天堂。
We estimate that the amount of corporate taxes lost as a result reached 10% of total corporate tax revenue in 2019, up from less than 0.1% in the 1970s.
我们估计，由此流失的公司税在2019年达到了公司税总收入的10%，而20世纪70年代还不到0.1%。
In 2019, the total government tax loss globally was $250 billion.
2019年，全球各国政府的税收损失总额为2500亿美元。
U.S. multinational corporations alone accounted for about half of that, followed by the U.K. and Germany.
仅美国的跨国公司就占了其中约一半，其次是英国和德国。
How do policymakers fix this?
政策制定者如何解决这个问题呢？
So far, the world as a whole has been trying to solve this problem by cutting or scrapping corporate taxes in a very gradual way.
到目前为止，全世界总体上一直试图通过一步一步、非常缓慢地削减或取消公司税来解决这个问题。
In the past 40 years, the global effective corporate tax rate has fallen from 23% to 17%.
在过去40年里，全球实际公司税率已从23%降至17%。
At the same time, governments have relied more heavily on consumption taxes.
与此同时，各国政府已更加依赖消费税。
But the root cause of profit-shifting is the incentives involved, such as generous or lenient corporate tax rates in other countries.
但利润转移的根本原因在于背后的利益诱因，比如其他国家优惠或宽松的公司税率。
If countries could agree on a global minimum corporate tax rate of, say, 20%, the problem of profit-shifting would largely disappear, as tax havens would simply cease to exist.
如果各国能就一个全球最低公司税率（比如20%）达成一致，利润转移问题就会基本消失，因为那样一来避税天堂就根本不存在了。
This type of mechanism is exactly what more than 130 countries signed on to in 2021, with implementation of a 15% minimum tax set to begin soon in the EU, U.K., Japan, Indonesia and many other countries.
2021年，130多个国家签约加入的正是这类机制，欧盟、英国、日本、印度尼西亚以及其他许多国家即将开始实施税率为15%的最低税。
The U.S. has notably not been able to pass this legislation.
值得注意的是，美国一直未能通过这项立法。
Our research suggests implementing this type of tax reform is necessary for reversing the shift of ever-greater amounts of corporate profits to tax havens—instead of these profits being taxed by the governments where the corporations operate and create value.
我们的研究表明，要扭转越来越多的公司利润被转移到避税天堂、而未由公司经营和创造价值所在地的政府征税的局面，就有必要实施这类税收改革。